<resources>
    <string name="app_name">CS Online</string>
    <string-array name="course_array">
        <item>CST 300: Major ProSeminar</item>
        <item>CST 338: Software Design</item>
        <item>CST 363: Database Management</item>
        <item>CST 334: Operating Systems</item>
        <item>CST 311: Introduction to Computer Networking</item>
        <item>CST 336: Internet Programming</item>
        <item>CST 462S: Race, Gender, Class in the Digital World</item>
        <item>CST 328: Digital Art and Design</item>
        <item>CST 370: Algorithms</item>
        <item>CST 383: Introduction to Data Science</item>
        <item>CST 329: Reasoning with Logic</item>
        <item>CST 438: Software Engineering</item>
        <item>CST 499: Directed Group Capstone</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="description_array">
        <item>
            Helps students identify and articulate personal, professional, and
            social goals. Provides an integrated overview of the computer science and communication
            design majors and their requirements. Students develop a plan for their learning goals.
            Students learn writing, presentation, research and critical-thinking skills within the
            diversified fields of information technology and communication design. Students learn how
            to analyze, predict, and articulate trends in the academic, public service, and private
            sectors.
        </item>
        <item>
            Provides students with the fundamental concepts to develop large-scale
            software, focusing on the object-oriented programming techniques. Coverage includes the
            introduction to Java programming language, object-oriented programming, software life cycle
            and development processes, requirements analysis, and graphical user interface development.
        </item>
        <item>
            This course provides balanced coverage of database use and design,focusing on relational
            databases. Students will learn to design relational schemas, write SQL queries, access a
            DB programmatically,and perform database administration. Students will gain a working
            knowledge of the algorithms and data structures used in query evaluation and transaction
            processing. Students will also learn to apply newer database technologies such as XML,
            NoSQL, and Hadoop.
        </item>
        <item>
            Students in this course will learn about the use and design of modern operating systems,
            focusing on Linux. On the “use” side, students will learn the Linux command line, to
            write shell scripts, and to build programs with GNU utilities like awk, sed, and make.
            On the “design” side, students will develop a deep understanding of process management,
            memory management, file systems, and concurrency, and how they apply to modern technologies
            like virtualization and cloud computing.
        </item>
        <item>
            Survey of Telecomm and Data Comm Technology Fundamentals, Local Area Network, Wide Area
            Network, Internet and internetworking protocols including TCP/IP, network security and
            performance, emerging industry trends such as voice over the network and high speed
            networking. Designed as a foundation for students who wish to pursue more advanced network
            studies including certificate programs. Includes hands-on networking labs that incorporate
            Cisco CCNA lab components.
        </item>
        <item>
            Provides students with dynamic web application development skills, focusing on the
            integration of server-side programming, database connectivity, and client-side scripting.
            Coverage includes the Internet architecture, responsive design, RESTful web services, and
            Web APIs.
        </item>
        <item>
            Provides students with key knowledge of race, gender, class and social justice especially
            in relation to technology in today’s digital world. Students challenge the barriers of
            expertise, gender, race, class, and location that restrict wider access to and understanding
            of the production and usage of new technologies. Students will engage in a practical
            experience in the community via their service placements, which will provide depth and
            context for considering questions of justice, equality, social responsibilities and the
            complexities of technology and its societal impact. The course uses scenario based approach
            combining presentations, discussions, and reflections to allow students explore the
            relationship between critical reflection and action on the topics mentioned above.
        </item>
        <item>
            A survey course that combines the study of technology, design and aesthetic principles
            as they apply to twenty-first century visual media. Students learn how fundamental concepts
            of art and design apply to a broad range of commercial, expressive and entertainment forms.
            Students also study the democratization of the creative process through digital media,
            using current technology to produce sophisticated and expressive examples of personal
            digital creativity.
        </item>
        <item>
            Students learn important data structures in computer science and acquire fundamental
            algorithm design techniques to get the efficient solutions to several computing problems
            from various disciplines. Topics include the analysis of algorithm efficiency, hash,
            heap, graph, tree, sorting and searching, brute force, divide-and-conquer,
            decrease-and-conquer, transform-and-conquer, dynamic programming, and greedy programming.
        </item>
        <item>
            In data science, data analysis and machine learning techniques are applied to visualize
            data, understand trends, and make predictions. In this course students will learn how to
            obtain data, preprocess it, apply machine learning methods, and visualize the results.
            A student who completes the course will have enough theoretical knowledge, and enough skill
            with modern statistical programming languages and their libraries,to define and perform
            complete data science projects.
        </item>
        <item>
            In this course students learn to develop skill in using logic to describe and assess arguments.
            Students will learn to write formulas in propositional and first-order logic, and more
            importantly, to write and check proofs. Students will also learn to write formulas in
            three-valued and modal logic, know how to choose an appropriate logic, and understand the
            limitations of logic in capturing human reasoning.
        </item>
        <item>
            Prepares students for large-scale software development using software engineering principles
            and techniques. Coverage includes software process, requirements analysis and specification,
            software design, implementation, testing, and project management. Students are expected to
            work in teams to carry out a realistic software project.
        </item>
        <item>
            Students will work on a project in large groups (up to 5 students in each group), developing
            requirements specification, a solution plan followed by design and implementation of the
            solution. The problem statement for the projects will be selected by the faculty. Faculty
            will also play the role of a project manager directing the schedule and deliverables for
            these projects.
        </item>
    </string-array>
</resources>